focusdiy.co.uk 2008-12-17

# security at Focus

**GENERAL TERMS AND CONDITIONS AND PRIVACY POLICY**

These General Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy set out the terms and conditions under which you may have access to, and use of, this Website (including all information, advice and downloaded materials contained or included by reference or access from it).

**Accuracy of Information**

The material contained on this Website has been prepared solely for the purpose of providing general information about Focus (DIY) Ltd ("Focus"), its subsidiaries and associated companies and the products and services they offer. While Focus has taken reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy of information contained herein, Focus makes no representation and gives no warranty, express or implied, as to the accuracy and completeness of any information on this Website. Focus accepts no responsibility for any omission or incompleteness of the information included on this Website. Focus reserves an absolute right to change or remove any piece of information contained herein at its sole discretion. Certain information on this Website is of a historical nature and may now be out of date. All historical information should be understood as speaking from the date of its original publication.

**Limitation of Liability**

Information contained on this Website is for general guidance only. Although We make every effort to ensure that information and advice on this Website is accurate, the appropriate materials, tools and methods can vary widely based on the specific facts involved. Accordingly, information provided on the Website is unlikely to be comprehensive. If you are inexperienced in carrying out DIY work, or are unsure of your abilities, you should always seek expert advice from appropriate qualified consultants and service providers. It is your responsibility to ensure that you read and follow all product use and safety information at all times.

The on-line help and advice service is provided to assist you with your DIY projects. Any advice is provided in good faith on the basis that the information supplied by you is complete and accurate. The advice should not be relied upon in substitution for appropriate professional expert advice.

Focus is unable to offer advice regarding electricity, gas or water. We recommend that you should always consult an appropriate professional electrician or CORGI registered plumber. Always read and follow any relevant manuals and safety instructions, and when working with electricity always turn off at the mains.

Focus does not exclude any liability for death or personal injury arising from our negligence or for fraudulent misrepresentation.

However, Focus does not accept liability to you for any costs, loss of profits, administrative inconvenience, disappointment, indirect or consequential loss or damage arising out of: 

* your use or inability to use the Website at any time and any error in the provision of the Website; and
* any use or reliance by you on information or advice published on or provided through the Website.

The entire liability of Focus under or in connection with the supply of information or advice from this Website whether for negligence, misrepresentation or otherwise, is limited, in respect of each event or series of connected events, to ?1000.

Focus does not represent or warrant the privacy and/or security of e-mails during internet transmission.

**Hyperlinks**

In the event that this Website from time to time contains any hypertext-links to other websites, Focus has not reviewed, is not responsible for, and accepts no liability in respect of, any information or opinion contained on any such other website. The inclusion of such hyperlinks, however, does not imply any endorsement or recommendation of those Websites or the contents of those Websites by Focus. Focus cannot give any undertaking that products you purchase from a third party to whose website We have provided a link on this Website will be of satisfactory quality and such warranties are DISCLAIMED by us absolutely. This does not affect your statutory rights against that third party seller. 

**Use of the Website**

The content of this Website and material herein are subject to copyright and other intellectual property rights, the ownership of which belongs to Focus. Any downloading, printing or copying from or other use of this Website or material contained on it shall not assign or transfer title or grant any right to any third party in respect of any software or other material on it. Focus grant you a non-exclusive personal licence, within the United Kingdom only, to access the content of this Website for your own personal domestic use, including copies of this Website on your computer and printing off hard copies for that purpose. This licence shall include information booklets and any other material downloaded from this Website. Focus has the right to revoke this licence at any time or to remove content from the scope of the licence. Focus makes no representation that any information or the content of this Website is appropriate or available for use in countries other than the United Kingdom. The material contained on this Website may not be modified, deleted, reproduced or used or otherwise made available for any other purpose without Focus' prior permission.

**DATA PROTECTION AND PRIVACY**

**Our privacy policy**

FOCUS is committed to protecting your privacy. Any personal information we collect will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws.

In this Data Protection and Privacy Policy references to "we" and "us" are to Focus.

**Control of personal information**

Any personal information provided to, or to be collected by, Focus is controlled primarily by Focus (DIY) Limited:

Contact details;

Registered office:  
Focus (DIY) Limited  
Gawsworth House  
Westmere Drive  
Crewe  
Cheshire  
CW1 6XB 

Registered in England under no. 1779190

To contact us by telephone please ring 01270 501555  
To contact us by email please mail to info@Focusdiy.co.uk

**What information do we collect and how do we use it?**

We will only collect information about individuals, where it is specifically and knowingly provided, for example, at the time of registration or at the time of ordering. This data is referred to in this policy as 'personal information'.  
When you register or order, we collect personal information to process and fulfil your order(s). When you place an order we will carry out security checks to protect against fraudulent transactions.  
We will also collect information concerning your marketing preferences. In accordance with your preferences, we may contact you; with offers and information about our goods and services; for market research purposes and to enable carefully selected third parties to contact you with offers and information about their goods and services. The information we collect will also be used to help us review, develop and improve the products and services we offer. You may change your preferences contacting us by post, email or telephone.

**Will Focus share the information it receives?**

We use third parties to carry out certain activities on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, carrying out surveys and installations, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These third parties have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.  
To protect against fraudulent transactions we may pass personal information to external agencies who will check the information we give them against public and private databases and may keep a record of such checks to use in future security checks.  
In accordance with the marketing preferences you select on this website or subsequently, we may share your personal information with carefully selected third parties so they may contact you with offers and information about their goods and services. You may change your preferences at any time by contacting us.  
We may share non-personal aggregate statistics (group) data about visitors to this site, sales and traffic patterns with connected group companies or other parties. However we do not sell or share any information about you as an individual user of this site unless you agree to us doing so.

Information may be transferred between Focus and its associated companies. Focus or relevant third parties transfer information to any country (including countries, which may not offer the same level of data protection as the UK). Although Focus takes steps to protect information within its possession, the nature of the Internet is such that the data may flow over networks without appropriate security measures and may be accessed and used by unauthorised persons.

**Cookies**

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and help us to track visitors to our site, so we can better understand what portions of our site best serve you.  
Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they do enable us to store items in your Shopping Basket between visits.  
Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to prevent this.  
It is not possible to purchase using www.Focusdiy.co.uk unless you have cookies turned on and we recommend that you leave them turned on.  
The 'help' portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. 

**Links**

We may from time to time establish relationships with other companies that will enable you to access the web sites of such companies directly from our site. Each individual company operates its own policy regarding the sale of personal information and the use of cookies. If you have a particular interest or concern regarding the way your personal information will be used then you are advised to read the privacy statement on the relevant site.  
We will try to provide you with links to high quality, reputable sites which we believe will be of interest and relevant to you, but please note that such third party sites are not under our control and we do not contribute to the content of such sites. When you click through to these sites you leave the area controlled by Focus. We cannot accept responsibility for any issues arising in connection with either the third party's use of your data, the site content or the services offered to you by these sites.

**How does Focus protect customer information?**

When you place orders or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. ****Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we are able to disclose sensitive information to you. ****It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you have finished using a shared computer.

**What choices do I have?**

You do not have to provide Focus with any of the information requested, however your computer will need to accept cookies to enable you to place orders with www.focusdiy.co.uk ****You may change your preferences by contacting us by post, email or telephone.

**Children**

Focus does not sell products for purchase by children. We sell children's products for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you may use www.focusdiy.co.uk only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

**How do I make a complaint to Focus?**

Focus will undertake to handle a complaint fairly and competently. We will keep you informed either by telephone or email at each stage and will endeavour to fully resolve your complaint within 48 hours. If you are still not happy with the way your complaint is being handled you should write to:

Customer Service Manager  
Focus DIY Limited  
Gawsworth House  
Westmere drive  
Crewe  
CW1 6XB

**Policy changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. Any changes to this policy made by Focus will be posted here and will take effect immediately. This policy was last updated in February 2007.

**Tell us what you think**

Focus welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. If you have any questions please contact us by post email or telephone.
